Guide to the Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives Collection of Environmentalism Serials TAM.732
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives Collection of Environmentalism Serials
1940-2004
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
Greenpeace USA
Institute for Social Ecology (Plainfield, Vt.)
Environmental Defense Fund
League of Conservation Voters
Friends of the Earth International.
Planet Drum Foundation
TRANET (Association)
TAM.732
8.75 Linear Feet in 7 record cartons, 1 half size manuscript box, and 1 oversize flat folder
The Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives Collection of Environmentalism Serials collection groups 241 titles broadly relating to environmentalism, published between 1940 and 2004, originally received by the Tamiment Library through subscriptions, donations, and as part of archival collections. The majority of the collection consists of incomplete runs of newspapers, newsletters, magazines, and bulletins published by environmental organizations, encompassing activist networks, research bodies, conservation groups, government agencies, independent farms and co-operatives, and non-profits and charities addressing various causes. The serials provide contemporaneous coverage of a wide range of issues of concern to environmentalists, broadly addressing ecological conditions and the various threats to a stable ecosystem; featuring reports on green initiatives, legal actions, and scientific findings; and providing guidance on sustainable living. A significant quantity of the collection dates from the 1970s and 1980s, when interest in and literacy around environmental issues surged, chronicling early mainstream discourse around sustainability and climate change.
Conditions Governing Access
Materials are opoen without restrictions.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
This collection combines serials relating to housing drawn from two discrete groups of material held by the Tamiment Library. The first was a partially inventoried backlog of serials received by the library through donations, subscriptions, and in archival collections. The second group consisted of around 1,700 serials, newspapers, and magazines, organized by title as an artificial collection, referred to as Periodicals.001 or Boxed Newspapers. This material was combined, inventoried, and arranged and described in subject-based categories in 2017. The accession number related to this collection is 2017.049.
Arrangement
Material is arranged at the file level, in alphabetical order by publication title, with issues of each publication organized chronologically. Each title is listed alongside its publishing organization and city of origin, where available.
Scope and Contents
The Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives Collection of Environmentalism Serials groups 241 titles broadly relating to environmentalism, published between 1940 and 2004, originally received by the Tamiment Library through subscriptions, donations, and as part of archival collections. The majority of the collection consists of incomplete runs of newspapers, newsletters, magazines, and bulletins, with a smaller quantity of one-off reports and catalogs, published by environmental organizations, encompassing activist networks, research bodies, conservation groups, government agencies, independent farms and co-operatives, and non-profits and charities. A significant quantity of the collection dates from the 1970s and 1980s, when interest in and literacy around environmental issues surged, chronicling early mainstream discourse around sustainability and climate change. The serials provide contemporaneous coverage of a wide range of issues of concern to environmentalists, broadly addressing ecological conditions and the various threats to a stable ecosystem; featuring reports on green initiatives, legal actions, and scientific findings; and providing guidance on sustainable living. Among the topics addressed in the serials are pollution (from toxic waste, pesticides, CFCs); agriculture (large and small scale farming, organic produce, sustainability); new technologies (solar, transport, recycling); conservation (deforestation, land preservation, endangered species protection and animal welfare more generally); and environmental policy (regulation, land use and public space, energy policy governing coal and nuclear power). The serials also contain discussion of intersectionally related causes, like pacifism and human rights, as well as some of the ideas and movements pioneered by environmentalists, including discussion of appropriate technology, food justice, co-operative living and farming, and the broadly defined 'alternative lifestyle.' The vast majority of the collection originates in and documents the United States, with publishing bodies including established, international organizations, like Greenpeace and Friends of the Earth, as well as smaller, grassroots groups operating on a local scale, often addressing specific topics - new infrastructures of food supply in a city, or a local site subject to pollution or development - in service of coordinating a community response. The topics addressed within the serials are often small scale - for example providing resources to facilitate a sustainable home life - but communicate the broader priorities and philosophies of environmental activists, addressing appropriate technology, alternative economies, resource conservation, and global inequity. Among the titles contained in this collection are issues of Building Economic Alternatives, Green Action, Green Letter, Not Man Apart, and TRANET, as well as various publications of the National Audubon Society, Planet Drum Foundation, ALTERNATIVES! Foundation, and the Sierra Club. Many of the serials include significant information on affiliated environmental organizations, including directories for local groups and educational resources. No complete runs of publications are contained herein, and generally only a handful of issues of each publication are held.
Antinuclear movement -- United States.; Appropriate technology; Green movement -- United States.; Environmentalism -- United States.; Wildlife conservation -- United States -- Periodicals.; Food cooperatives
- Action Bulletin: Citizens' Clearinghouse for Hazardous Waste, Arlington, VA, 1986 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Adirondack Activist: Northeast Regional Office of the National Audubon Society, Albany, NY, 1992 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Adirondack Advocate: National Audubon Society, Albany, NY, 1993 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Adirondack Council Newsletter: Adirondack Council, Elizabethtown, NY, 1985-1995 (Box 1, Folder 4-5)
- Alaska Conservation Foundation Dispatch: Alaska Conservation Foundation, Anchorage, AK, 1993-1995 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Alert!: Washington Environmental Council, Seattle, WA, 1983-1987 (Box 1, Folder 7-8)
- Alliance: Oregon Coalition of Alternative Human Services, Portland, OR, 1982-1987 (Box 1, Folder 9-10)
- Alternate Currents: Appropriate Technology Action Coalition, New York, NY, 1979 (Box 1, Folder 11)
- Alternative Foundations: School of Environmental Studies, Ramapo College, Mahwah, NJ, 1984 (Box 1, Folder 12)
- ALTERNATIVES! Foundation Newsletter: ALTERNATIVES! Foundation, Berkeley, CA, 1970-1971 (Box 1, Folder 13)
- Americans for Energy Independence: Washington, DC, 1986 (Box 1, Folder 14)
- Amicus Journal: The Natural Resources Defense Council, New York, NY, 1984-1985, 1999 (Box 1, Folder 15)
- Animalia: World Federation for the Protection of Animals, Zurich, Switzerland, 1976 (Box 1, Folder 16)
- Animals' Agenda: Animal Rights Network, Westport, CT, 1988 (Box 1, Folder 17-18)
- Argonaut: Atlantic Chapter of the Sierra Club, New York, NY, 1972 (Box 1, Folder 19)
- Audobon Activist Special Report: Audobon Activist, New York, NY, circa 1988 (Box 1, Folder 20)
- Audubon Options: National Audubon Society, New York, NY, 1995 (Box 1, Folder 21)
- Auto-Free Press: Auto-Free New York/Transportation Alternatives, New York, NY, 1991-1993 (Box 1, Folder 22)
- Bay Watcher: Save San Francisco Bay Association, Oakland, CA, 1988-1995 (Box 1, Folder 23-24)
- Bear News: Great Bear Foundation, Missoula, MT, 1991 (Box 1, Folder 25)
- Birdscope: Cornell Laboratory of Ornithology, Ithaca, NY, 1989-1990 (Box 1, Folder 26)
- Bridging the Gap: Government Accountability Project, Washington, DC, 1991-1995 (Box 1, Folder 27)
- Building Economic Alternatives: Co-op America, Inc., Washington, DC, 1985-1991 (Box 1, Folder 28-29)
- Bulletin: Saw Mill River Audubon Society, Inc., Chappaqua, NY, 1993-1995 (Box 1, Folder 30)
- Catalyst: Union of Concerned Scientists, Cambridge, MA, 2002-2004 (Box 1, Folder 31)
- CEE Report: Center for Environmental Education, Washington, DC, 1984-1988 (Box 1, Folder 32-33)
- Chapter News: American Littoral Society, Highlands, NJ, 1989-1990 (Box 1, Folder 34)
- CIP Bulletin: Center for the Biology of Natural Systems, St. Louis, MO, 1980 (Box 1, Folder 35)
- Clamshell Alliance News: Clamshell Alliance, Seabrook, NH, 1977-1979 (Box 8, Folder 1)
- Clearinghouse Bulletin: Carrying Capacity Network, Washington, DC, 1993 (Box 1, Folder 36)
- Coastal Reporter: American Littoral Society, Highlands, NJ, 1989-1995 (Box 1, Folder 37)
- Columbiana: Columbia River Bioregional Education Project, Oroville, WA, 1987-1993 (Box 1, Folder 38-40)
- Common Sense: Travis County Green Party, Austin, TX, 2002 (Box 1, Folder 41)
- Communities: Fellowship for International Community, Fort Collins, CO, 1994 (Box 2, Folder 1)
- Conserve Neighborhoods: National Trust for Historic Preservation, Washington, DC, 1981 (Box 2, Folder 2)
- Contretemps: Coopérative d'information et de recherche écologiste du Québec, Quebec, Canada, 1989 (Box 2, Folder 3)
- Crabshell Brief: Crabshell Alliance, Seattle, WA, 1980-1982 (Box 2, Folder 4)
- Critical Mass Journal: Critical Mass Energy Project, Washington, DC, 1978-1979 (Box 8, Folder 2)
- Currents: Citizens United for Responsible Energy, Des Moines, IA, 1981 (Box 8, Folder 3)
- Cycle: Environmental Action Coalition, New York, NY, 1990 (Box 2, Folder 5)
- Dead Serious: Workers for Safe Energy & Black Hills Alliance, Milwaukee, WI, 1979 (Box 2, Folder 6)
- Del-Aware Citizens Voice: Del-Aware Unlimited, Inc., New Hope, PA, 1983 (Box 2, Folder 7)
- EARS: Energy Catalog: EARS - Environmental Action Reprint Service, Denver, CO, circa 1977 (Box 2, Folder 8)
- EARS: Nuclear Information Catalog: EARS - Environmental Action Reprint Service, La Veta, CO, circa 1977 (Box 2, Folder 9)
- Earth Belongs to the People: Peoples Press, San Francisco, CA, 1970 (Box 2, Folder 10-11)
- Earth Council Journal: Earth Council Journal, Catasaqua, PA, circa 1990 (Box 2, Folder 12)
- Earth Ethics: Public Resource Foundation, Washington, DC, 1990 (Box 2, Folder 13)
- Earth First!: Earth First!, Missoula, MT, circa 1990 (Box 2, Folder 14)
- Earth Kit: ENVIRONMENT!, New York, NY, circa 1970s (Box 2, Folder 15)
- Earth Times: Earth Times Foundation, New York, NY, 1998 (Box 2, Folder 16)
- Earth Week NYC: E.D.E.N. Project, New York, NY, 1990 (Box 2, Folder 17)
- Earthcare Northwest: Seattle Audubon Society, Seattle, WA, 1983-1987 (Box 2, Folder 18-19)
- EarthTimes: San Francisco, CA, 1970 (Box 2, Folder 20)
- Eco-Sources Environmental and Natural Resources Directory: Echo Ranch Media Project, New York, NY, 1984 (Box 2, Folder 21)
- EcoAlert: Environmental Task Force, Washington, DC, 1983-1985 (Box 2, Folder 22)
- Ecologist Report: The Ecologist, London, England, 2001 (Box 2, Folder 23)
- Ecology and Development: Ecology Research Committee, City College of New York, New York, NY, 1970 (Box 2, Folder 24)
- EDF Letter: Environmental Defense Fund, Washington, DC, 1975-1995, 1997 (Box 2, Folder 25-28)
- EDF News Clips: Environmental Defense Fund, Inc., New York, NY, 1997 (Box 2, Folder 29)
- EDF Reports: Environmental Defense Fund, New York, NY, 1975, 1985, 1987, 1989-1992 (Box 2, Folder 30)
- eeac: Environmental Education Advisory Council, New York, NY, 1985 (Box 3, Folder 1)
- Eli News: Environmental Law Institute, Washington, DC, 1995 (Box 3, Folder 2)
- Energy Economist: An International Analysis: Financial Business Times Information, London, UK, 1989-1990 (Box 3, Folder 3)
- Energy News Digest: Citizens Energy Council, Allendale, NJ, 1981 (Box 8, Folder 4)
- Environmental Outlook: Institute for Environmental Studies, University of Washington, Seattle, WA, 1983-1988 (Box 3, Folder 4)
- EPOCA Update: Environmental Project on Central America, San Francisco, CA, 1991 (Box 3, Folder 5)
- Executive Director's Quarterly Report: Union of Concerned Scientists, Cambridge, MA, 1993 (Box 3, Folder 6)
- Flicker: Adirondack Nature Conservancy, Keene Valley, NY, 1991-1993, 1995 (Box 3, Folder 7)
- Focus: World Wildlife Fund-U.S., Washington, DC, 1983, 1995 (Box 3, Folder 8)
- Food Conspiracy: Food Conspiracy Cooperative, Tucson, AZ, 1983-1986 (Box 3, Folder 9-10)
- Food is for People: People's Warehouse, New York, NY, 1973 (Box 3, Folder 11)
- Forest Action Network Newsletter: Forest Action Network, Vancouver, BC, Canada, 1996 (Box 3, Folder 12)
- Free Report: Fund for Renewable Energy & the Environment, Washington, DC, 1987 (Box 3, Folder 13)
- Friends of Clayoquot Sound: Friends of Clayoquot Sound, Tofino, Canada, 1988, 1994 (Box 3, Folder 14)
- Friends of the Earth: Friends of the Earth, Washington, DC, 1994-1995 (Box 3, Folder 15)
- Garden News: New York Botanical Garden, Bronx, NY, 1991-1992, 1995 (Box 3, Folder 16)
- Gorilla: Gorilla Foundation, Woodside, CA, 1986-1995 (Box 3, Folder 17-18)
- Green Action: Rhythm & News Publishers & Distributors, Tempe, AZ, 1986-1990 (Box 3, Folder 19)
- Green Brigades: Ecologists' Paper: Foundation for the Support of Ecological Initiatives, Krakow, Poland, 1993-1994 (Box 3, Folder 20)
- Green Consensus: San Francisco Greens, San Francisco, CA, 1990 (Box 3, Folder 21)
- Green Drummer: Greenworking, Pleasantville, NY, 1994 (Box 3, Folder 22)
- Green Letter: Tides Foundation, Berkeley, CA, circa 1987-1991 (Box 3, Folder 23-24)
- Green Line: Green Line, Oxford, UK, 1984-1985 (Box 3, Folder 25)
- Green Mountain Monitor: Green Mountain Forest Watch, Brattleboro, VT, 1994 (Box 3, Folder 26)
- Green Perspectives: Green Program Project, Burlington, VT, 1986, 1996 (Box 3, Folder 27)
- Green Revolution: School of Living, York, PA, 1984-1985 (Box 3, Folder 28)
- Green Scene: Greens of San Diego, San Diego, CA, 1990 (Box 3, Folder 29)
- Green Synthesis: League for Ecological Democracy, San Pedro, CA, 1988-1989 (Box 3, Folder 30)
- Green Voices: New York Greens, New York, NY, 1985 (Box 3, Folder 31)
- GreenGram: Green Party of New Jersey, Trenton, NJ, 2003 (Box 3, Folder 32)
- Greenpeace (Quarterly): Greenpeace USA, Washington, DC, 1987-1997 (Box 3, Folder 33-37)
- Greenpeace Action: Greenpeace Action, Washington, DC, 1989 (Box 3, Folder 38)
- Greenpeace Examiner: Greenpeace USA, Portland, OR, 1981-1986 (Box 3, Folder 39-41)
- Greenpeace Magazine: Greenpeace, Washington, DC, 1991, 1997 (Box 4, Folder 1)
- Greenspeak: New York Greens, New York, NY, 1986 (Box 4, Folder 2)
- Ground Work: Tides Foundation, Berkeley, CA, 1992-1994 (Box 4, Folder 3)
- Ground Work Extra!: Groundwork Magazine, 1995 (Box 4, Folder 4)
- Guide: Mid Atlantic Rainbow Outreach, Washington, DC, 1985 (Box 4, Folder 5)
- Harbinger: Institute for Social Ecology, Rochester, VT, 1983, 1985 (Box 4, Folder 6-7, Box 9, Folder 1)
- Health Aspects of Pesticides - Abstract Bulletin: Environmental Protection Agency, Washington, DC, 1971 (Box 4, Folder 8)
- HomeFront: Rocky Mountain Front Advisory Council, Missoula, MT, 1994 (Box 4, Folder 9)
- How Safe is New Mexico's Atomic City?: Southwest Research and Information Center, Albuquerque, NM, 1980 (Box 4, Folder 10)
- Hudson Valley Green Times: Hudson Valley Grass Roots Energy & Environmental Network, Inc. (GREEN), Brooklyn, NY, 1985, 1991, 1994 (Box 4, Folder 11)
- Initiatives of the New York Greens: New York Greens, New York, NY, 1987 (Box 4, Folder 12)
- Inland Empire Public Lands Council: Inland Empire Public Lands Council, Coeur d'Alene, ID, 1987 (Box 4, Folder 13)
- Inner Voice: Association of Forest Service Employees for Environmental Ethics, Eugene, OR, 1995 (Box 4, Folder 14)
- Jersey Green: N.J. Citizens Party, Highland Park, NJ, 1982, 1995 (Box 4, Folder 15)
- Jersey Greens Journal: Greens, Princeton, NJ, 1994-1995 (Box 4, Folder 16)
- Journal of Heredity, 1949 (Box 4, Folder 17)
- Journal of Pesticide Reform: Northwest Coaition for Alternatives to Pesticides, Eugene, OR, 1985-1988 (Box 4, Folder 18-19)
- Kate Mullany House, Troy, NY: National Park Service - U.S. Department of the Interior, Boston, MA, 2004 (Box 4, Folder 20)
- land is life: Northern California Land Trust, San Francisco, CA, 1978 (Box 4, Folder 21)
- Land Lines: Nature Conservancy Lower Hudson Chapter, Mount Kisco, NY, 1980-1988 (Box 4, Folder 22)
- Last Gasp! = Les etouffes: Environmental Working Group, Quebec, Canada, 1981-1982 (Box 4, Folder 23)
- LCV Insider: League of Conservation Voters, Washington, DC, 1990-1995 (Box 4, Folder 24)
- League of Conservative Voters: New England/Mid-Atlantic Regional Scorecard (moved to L for "LCV"): League of Conservation Voters, Washington, DC, 1996 (Box 4, Folder 24)
- Learning Alliance: Institute for Social Ecology, New York, NY, 1985 (Box 4, Folder 25)
- Left Green Notes: Left Green Network, Burlington, VT, 1991 (Box 4, Folder 26)
- Left Green Perspectives: Social Ecology Project, Burlington, VT, 1998-2000 (Box 4, Folder 27)
- Lightwheels: Lightwheels, Inc., New York, NY, 1990 (Box 4, Folder 28)
- Littorally Speaking: American Littoral Society, Highlands, NJ, 1991-1995 (Box 4, Folder 29)
- Live Wild or Die: Portland, OR, circa 1989 (Box 4, Folder 30)
- Lovin' FORCful: Federation of Ohio River Co-ops (FORC), Columbus, OH, 1980 (Box 4, Folder 31)
- Malahierba: prensa alternativa: Malahierba, Valencia, Spain, 1984 (Box 4, Folder 32)
- Marine Conservation News: Center for Marine Conservation, Washington, DC, 1989-1996 (Box 4, Folder 33-36)
- Members' Bulletin: Wildlife Conservation Society (AND) New York Zoological Society, New York, NY, 1992-1994 (Box 4, Folder 37)
- Mendocino County Environmentalist: Ukiah, CA, 1991 (Box 4, Folder 38)
- Midland Cooperator: Co-op Press, Inc., Minneapolis, MN, 1949, 1951 (Box 4, Folder 39-40)
- Mobilization for Animals: Columbus, OH, circa 1983 (Box 4, Folder 41)
- Modern Utopian: ALTERNATIVES! Foundation, Berkeley, CA, 1969 (Box 4, Folder 42)
- MSES: Metropolitan Solar Energy Society, New York, NY, 1980 (Box 4, Folder 43)
- Muir and Friends: Friends of the Earth and John Muir Institute for Environmental Studies, San Francisco, CA, 1970 (Box 4, Folder 44)
- MX Update: MX Information Center, Salt Lake City, UT, 1982 (Box 4, Folder 45)
- Myths and Techno-Fantasies: The Black Mesa Defense Fund, Santa Fe, NM, circa 1971 (Box 4, Folder 46)
- N.Y. Mobilizer: NY Mobilization for Survival, New York, NY, 1981-1986 (Box 5, Folder 1)
- National Energy Program: UAW, Detroit, MI, 1974 (Box 5, Folder 2)
- Natural: Colectivo Ecologista, Madrid, Spain, 1989 (Box 5, Folder 3)
- Nature Conservancy: New York State, Albany, NY, 1989-1992 (Box 5, Folder 4)
- Nature Conservancy: Lower Hudson Chapter, Mount Kisco, NY, 1988-1995 (Box 5, Folder 5)
- NCAP News: Northwest Coaition for Alternatives to Pesticides, Eugene, OR, 1983-1985 (Box 5, Folder 6)
- New Catalyst: Catalyst Education Society, Lillooet, Canada, 1989 (Box 5, Folder 7)
- New England Green Action: New England Green Alliance, Berlington, VT, 1990 (Box 5, Folder 8)
- New Times: Silver Owl Publications, Inc, Seattle, WA, 1986-1987 (Box 5, Folder 9-10)
- New York Botanical Garden Member's Update: New York Botanical Garden, Bronx, NY, 1986-1990 (Box 5, Folder 11)
- New York Notes: Nature Conservancy, Albany, NY, 1987 (Box 5, Folder 12)
- News Letter: Way of Life Co-op, Pleasantville, NY, 1993 (Box 5, Folder 13)
- NewsJournal of the National Audubon Society: National Audubon Society, New York, NY, 1986 (Box 5, Folder 14)
- Newsletter: Institute for Social Ecology, Rochester, VT, 1986 (Box 5, Folder 19)
- Newsletter: Adirondack Architectural Heritage, Keeseville, NY, 1992, 1994-1995 (Box 5, Folder 15)
- Newsletter: Horticultural Society of New York, New York, NY, 1985 (Box 5, Folder 18)
- Newsletter: Lawyer's Committee on Nuclear Policy, New York, NY, 1985 (Box 5, Folder 20)
- Newsletter: Nature Conservancy of New York, Albany, NY, 1995 (Box 5, Folder 21)
- Newsletter: Cascadia Green Alliance, Seattle, WA, 1986 (Box 5, Folder 16)
- Newsletter: Columbia River Bioregional Education Project, Oroville, WA, 1992 (Box 5, Folder 17)
- Newsline: Natural Resources Defense Council, New York, NY, 1991-1992 (Box 5, Folder 22, Box 9, Folder 2-3)
- NIRS Alert: Nuclear Information and Resource Service, Washington, DC, 1985 (Box 5, Folder 23)
- Nisqually Delta Association News Bulletin: Nisqually Delta Association, Olympia, WA, 1979 (Box 5, Folder 24)
- Noise Pollution Flyer: Citizens for a Quieter City, New York, NY, circa 1960s (Box 5, Folder 25)
- North Woods Vision: RESTORE: The North Woods, Concord, MA, 1993-1995 (Box 5, Folder 26)
- Northeastern Union Farmer: Farmers Defender, Inc., Ogdensburg, NY, 1955-1958 (Box 5, Folder 27)
- Northern Forest Forum: Northern Appalachian Restoration Project of Earth Island Institute, Lancaster, NH, 1994 (Box 5, Folder 28)
- Northern Thunder's Hard Rain: Northern Thunder, Eau Claire, WI, 1982 (Box 5, Folder 29)
- Not Man Apart: Friends of the Earth, John Muir Institute for Environmental Studies and the League of Conservation Voters, San Francisco, CA, 1970-1974, 1977, 1982-1990 (Box 5, Folder 30-38, Box 6, Folder 1-11)
- Notes from Underground: Committee for Better Transit, Inc., Long Island City, NY, 1976 (Box 6, Folder 12)
- Nuclear Hazards: Citizens Energy Council, Allendale, NJ, 1986 (Box 6, Folder 13)
- Nuclear Notes: NYC SHAD Alliance, New York, NY, 1988 (Box 6, Folder 14)
- Nucleus: Union of Concerned Scientists, Cambridge, MA, 1986, 1991-1997 (Box 6, Folder 15-18)
- NYPIRG's Agenda for citizen involvement: New York Public Interest Research Group, Inc., New York, NY, 1986 (Box 6, Folder 19)
- On The Front...: Badger-Two Medicine Alliance, Missoula, MT, 1993 (Box 6, Folder 20)
- PAWS News: Progressive Animal Welfare Society, Lynnwood, WA, 1983-1985 (Box 6, Folder 21)
- People & Energy: Citizens' Energy Project, Washington, DC, 1978 (Box 6, Folder 22)
- People's Energy Movement: Movement for a New Society, Philadelphia, PA, 1980 (Box 6, Folder 23)
- People's Energy Primer: Syracuse Peace Council, Syracuse, NY, 1979 (Box 6, Folder 24)
- Planetary Citizen: Planetary Citizen Registry, Ottawa, Canada, 1972 (Box 6, Folder 25)
- Portland Alliance, The: Oregon Coalition of Alternative Human Services, Portland, OR, 1978-1986 (Box 8, Folder 5)
- Predator Project Newsletter: Environmentalism, Bozeman, MT, 1996 (Box 6, Folder 26)
- Preserve Appalachian Wilderness: Preserve Appalachian Wilderness Network Inc. (PAW NET), Brattleboro, VT, circa 1996 (Box 6, Folder 27)
- Puget Sound Cooperative Federation Newsletter: Puget Sound Cooperative Federation, Seattle, WA, 1983-1984, 1986 (Box 6, Folder 28)
- Puget Sound Notes: Washington State Department of Ecology, Olympia, WA, 1985-1987 (Box 6, Folder 29)
- PVC - The Poison Plastic: Greenpeace, Washington, DC, 1997 (Box 6, Folder 30)
- Quarterly Report: Puget Sound Water Quality Authority, Seattle, WA, 1987 (Box 6, Folder 31)
- Radioactivist: Citizen's Awareness Network, New York, NY, 1999 (Box 6, Folder 32)
- Rain: Rain Umbrella, Inc., Portland, OR, 1978-1981 (Box 6, Folder 33-34)
- Rainbow Bridge: New York Rainbow, New York, NY, 1998 (Box 6, Folder 35)
- Raise the Stakes: Planet Drum Foundation, San Francisco, CA, 1981-1984, 1987 (Box 6, Folder 36)
- Re:Sources: Environmental Task Force, Washington, DC, 1983-1986 (Box 7, Folder 1-2)